As part of running an app or even testing an
app, we can, in some situations, use command-line
arguments to run the app. Using command-line
arguments allows us to run an app multiple
ways without changing the code within the app. For
this example, I have a file named 323-command that
writes text to a file and then prints a message
that the file is complete. I want to run this code
from a command line so that we can test calling
this code from outside the Python development
environment. Instead of running the code from
Visual Studio, I have a command prompt open,
and I have navigated to the folder containing the
Python file we just looked at. I will type python
and then the file name, 323-command.py, and
then select the Enter key on the keyboard. The
file runs, and we get the output from the print
statement. Again, running Python from the command
line allows one to test small blocks of code or
even complete files without being in a development
environment, thus allowing people who have the
Python engine installed, but no development
environment installed to test code, helping ensure
an app works. There are a couple of important
points that might cause problems. First, if
you're running Python files from the command line,
make sure Python is set as an environment variable
on your system. If it isn't, you could encounter
some problems trying to run your code. How to set
this up varies depending on your operating system,
so you might want to look up specific instructions
for your setup. Secondly, a quick heads-up about
Python versions: features like f-strings are only
available in Python 3.6 and later. If you're using
an older version, you won't be able to utilize
these convenient features. It might be a good
idea to check your Python version and consider
upgrading if you're working with an outdated
version. We have reached the halfway point in
this course, and now it’s time for you to take the
skills you have learned and build an entire Python
project. The instructions for what is warranted
is in the Review 3.2 exercise in your project
workbook. Allow yourself to conceptualize what is
needed to generate the output in the exercise and,
if necessary, write down or even map out the logic
needed to make the code necessary for the output.
There is no one perfect answer to this project,
but I will tell you this hint: you should
be able to get this done in under 15 lines
of code. Make it happen, and I will see you
with one potential answer in the next video.